<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Graham Montgomery</title>
    <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Graham Montgomery</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:40:11 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://grahammontgomery.eco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:40:11 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/about/</guid>
      <description> Contact Graham Montgomery&#xA;PhD Candidate | Tingley Lab&#xA;​Department of Ecology &amp;amp; Evolutionary Biology&#xA;University of California, Los Angeles&#xA;Los Angeles, CA, USA 90095&#xA;email: montgomery.graham@gmail.com&#xA;​ Contributory science: see iNaturalist, eBird, and BugGuide. Personal He/him/his. In my free time, I enjoy kayaking, backpacking, reading, playing basketball, and hanging out with my cat. CV (pdf) My recent observations on iNaturalist </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:39:54 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/research/</guid>
      <description>PhD research My dissertation is focused on understanding insect declines &amp;amp; how insectivorous birds are affected. I am especially interested in&#xA;Ecological monitoring &amp;amp; methods standardization Insect population dynamics &amp;amp; variability Using resurvey data to understand insect &amp;amp; bird community change over time To answer these questions, I use a variety of approaches, including field surveys, crowd-sourced science, &amp;amp; rigorous evidence synthesis (like the entoGEM project). Research + My main training is in ornithology &amp;amp; entomology, but I am fundamentally an ecologist interested in everything.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birds</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/birds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:39:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/birds/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black-and-white</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/black_and_white/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:39:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/black_and_white/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feathers</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/feathers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:39:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/feathers/</guid>
      <description>Macrophotography isn&amp;rsquo;t just for bugs&amp;hellip;! Feathers are wondrous structures. They are light but strong, disposable but durable, simple but intricate. We usually see feathers only as parts of the beautiful whole that makes up a bird’s plumage, but at a smaller scale, each individual feather is just as remarkable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insects (&amp; more) on color</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/insects_on_color/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:39:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/insects_on_color/</guid>
      <description>Here are some photos of invertebrates on color backgrounds (more at iNaturalist):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insects (and more) on white backgrounds</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/insects_on_white/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:39:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/insects_on_white/</guid>
      <description>I like this effect since I think it brings out the personality of each individual. It also allows for easy seamless integration into field guides. You can find many more of my photos in this style on iNaturalist. Check out the Inverts on White Backgrounds project while you&amp;rsquo;re there!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Landscape</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:39:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/landscape/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portrait</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/portrait/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:39:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/photography/portrait/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to paddle the Mississippi River from source to sea</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/writing/mississippi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/writing/mississippi/</guid>
      <description>Interested in paddling America’s great river from source to sea, or maybe a section of it? There are some really nice resources out there already (see below), but I will try to supplement them here. I kayaked the Mississippi solo in the fall of 2016, and it was the trip of a lifetime. It took me 62 days and over one million paddles to travel the 2100 miles of river on my route (~3500 km)!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insect families of the US &amp; Canada</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/resources/bugfams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/resources/bugfams/</guid>
      <description>This is a list of all the insect families found in the United States and Canada, organized by order, and curated by GM. If you find any errors, please contact GM at montgomery.graham AT gmail.com. Taxonomic authorities used as references for this list can be found at the bottom of the page.&#xA;Order Family Common name Archaeognatha Machilidae Jumping bristletails Archaeognatha Meinertellidae Rock bristletails Zygentoma Lepidotrichidae Forest silverfish Zygentoma Lepismatidae True silverfish** Zygentoma Nicoletiidae Subterranean silverfish Ephemeroptera Acanthametropodidae Sand-dwelling mayflies Ephemeroptera Ameletidae Comb-mouthed minnow mayflies* Ephemeroptera Ametropodidae Sand minnows Ephemeroptera Arthropleidae Flat-headed mayflies* Ephemeroptera Baetidae Small minnow mayflies Ephemeroptera Baetiscidae Armored mayflies Ephemeroptera Behningiidae Tuskless burrower mayflies Ephemeroptera Caenidae Small square-gilled mayflies* Ephemeroptera Ephemerellidae Spiny crawler mayflies Ephemeroptera Ephemeridae Common burrower mayflies Ephemeroptera Euthyplociidae n/a Ephemeroptera Heptageniidae Flat-headed mayflies* Ephemeroptera Isonychiidae Brush-legged mayflies* Ephemeroptera Leptohyphidae Little stout crawler mayflies Ephemeroptera Leptophlebiidae Prong-gilled mayflies* Ephemeroptera Metretopodidae Cleft-footed minnow mayflies Ephemeroptera Neoephemeridae Large square-gilled mayflies* Ephemeroptera Oligoneuriidae Brush-legged mayflies* Ephemeroptera Palingeniidae Spiny-headed burrower mayflies* Ephemeroptera Polymitarcyidae Pale burrower mayflies Ephemeroptera Potamanthidae Hacklegill mayflies Ephemeroptera Pseudironidae Crabwalker mayflies Ephemeroptera Siphlonuridae Primitive minnow mayflies Odonata Aeshnidae Darners Odonata Calopterygidae Broad-winged damselflies Odonata Coenagrionidae Narrow-winged damselflies Odonata Cordulegastridae Spiketails; Biddies Odonata Corduliidae Emeralds; Green-eyed skimmers Odonata Gomphidae Clubtails Odonata Lestidae Spreadwings; Stalked-winged damselflies Odonata Libellulidae Skimmers Odonata Macromiidae Cruisers; Belted skimmers Odonata Petaluridae Petaltails; Graybacks Odonata Protoneuridae Threadtails; tropical damselflies Zoraptera Zorotypidae Angel insects Dermaptera Anisolabididae n/a Dermaptera Forficulidae Common earwigs Dermaptera Labiduridae Long-horned earwigs; striped earwigs Dermaptera Spongiphoridae Little earwigs Plecoptera Capniidae Small winter stoneflies Plecoptera Chloroperlidae Green stoneflies Plecoptera Leuctridae Rolled-winged stoneflies Plecoptera Nemouridae Spring stoneflies Plecoptera Peltoperlidae Roach-like stoneflies Plecoptera Perlidae Common stoneflies Plecoptera Perlodidae Predatory stoneflies Plecoptera Pteronarcyidae Giant stoneflies Plecoptera Taeniopterygidae Winter stoneflies Orthoptera Acrididae Short-horned grasshoppers Orthoptera Anostostomatidae Wetas &amp;amp; King crickets; Silk-spinning crickets Orthoptera Eumastacidae Monkey grasshoppers Orthoptera Gryllacrididae Raspy crickets; Leaf-rolling crickets Orthoptera Gryllidae True crickets Orthoptera Gryllotalpidae Mole crickets Orthoptera Mogoplistidae Scaly crickets Orthoptera Myrmecophilidae Ant crickets Orthoptera Oecanthidae Tree crickets Orthoptera Prophalangopsidae Hump-winged crickets; Grigs Orthoptera Rhaphidophoridae Camel crickets Orthoptera Ripipterygidae Mud crickets Orthoptera Romaleidae Lubber grasshoppers Orthoptera Stenopelmatidae Jerusalem crickets Orthoptera Tanaoceridae Desert long-horned grasshoppers Orthoptera Tetrigidae Pygmy grasshoppers; grouse locusts; groundhoppers Orthoptera Tettigoniidae Katydids Orthoptera Tridactylidae Pygmy mole crickets Orthoptera Trigonidiidae Ground crickets/Wood crickets &amp;amp; Sword-tail crickets (Ground crickets &amp;amp; allies?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recommended ID resources</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/resources/identification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/resources/identification/</guid>
      <description>My preferred comprehensive ID resources for North America north of Mexico*&#xA;Butterflies | A Swift Guide to Butterflies of North America by Glassberg Tiger beetles | A Field Guide to the Tiger Beetles of the United States and Canada by Pearson, et al. Dragonflies | Dragonflies and Damselflies of the East (and the western edition) by Paulson Bumblebees | Bumble Bees of North America: An Identification Guide by Williams et al.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The BioChallenge Game</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/writing/biochallenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/writing/biochallenge/</guid>
      <description>In the spirit of birding, I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with a game that celebrates the incredible biodiversity around us. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple: tally up all the types of life you&amp;rsquo;ve seen. You get one point for each unique species, two points for each genus, 3 points for a family, 4 points for an order, 5 points for a class, and 10 points for a phylum. Add them all up (made easier through iNaturalist, Bugguide, and eBird) and see what you get!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mistletoebird</title>
      <link>https://grahammontgomery.eco/writing/the_mistletoebird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grahammontgomery.eco/writing/the_mistletoebird/</guid>
      <description>How mistletoe got associated with Christmas is a bit of a mystery, but it’s probably because mistletoe is one of the few plant species that is green even in the winter. Imagine planning a winter celebration around 900 AD in northern Europe (just ignore the serfdom and disease for a moment): one of the few plants you could use for decoration would be mistletoe, since most other plants have either lost their leaves or died back in the middle of winter.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
